

Alex Rohleder

Frontend software engineer with 6 years of experience

& +47 412 44 953

 $@ \ a lex rohleder 96@gmail.com\\$

☑ linkedin.com/in/alexrohleder

☑ twitter.com/alexrohleder

⊚ Trondheim, Norway

☑ github.com/alexrohleder

Summary

Hey! I'm a Brazilian who is passionate about building high-impact, well-performing user experiences.

I believe that work is a big portion of my day, so I try to make the best out of it for me and my colleagues.

To achieve that I focus on empathy during conversations and try to deliver something I'm happy with.

Experience

5 years as full-time and 1 year as intern.

Sportradar - Software Engineer (Senior)

☐ 03/2018 - Ongoing · 3 yrs 7 mos ⑤ Trondheim, Norway

Sportradar is the world's leading sports data company, have clients like NHL, NBA, FIFA and NASCAR.

- · Improved DX for micro-frontend teams. One of the achieved results was a reduction of avg. 70% in build times;
- · Reduced by 87% the number of software vulnerabilities over two teams, either by triage or by development advising;
- Resolves performance issues on applications with high level of data updates or high amount of data;
- · Supports hiring, onboarding and mentoring new employees;

Meta - Software Engineer (Mid-level)

□ 03/2016 - 01/2018 · 1 yrs 10 mos ⊚ Recanto Maestro, Brazil

Meta is an international IT outsourcing enterprise, have clients like Sascar, Unimed and O Boticário.

- Responsible for deployments of critical applications that would lead to severe impact to business in case of downtimes;
- · Worked with different development methodologies, such as Scrum and variations, accordingly with clients choice;
- · Nominated as the technical reference for PHP outsourcing, helped on architecting and kick-starting multiple projects;
- Represented the company in conversations with clients, understanding their problems and taking technical decisions to solve them;

There is three working experiences that are not listed.

What sets me apart?

- I demonstrate strong performance so colleagues can rely upon me.
- I'm self-motivated with a passion for learning and using front-end technology.
- I'm a systems thinker who can reason through systems and understand technical tradeoffs.

Expertise How confortable I'm with each technology JavaScript (5+ years) TypeScript (3+ years) React (4 years + courses) Non-exhaustive list of languages, technologies and tools Redux GraphQL Jest Kubernetes AWS Micro-Frontends Node.js

Education

- Information Systems BSc
- Advanced Patterns React Live AMS
 And more trainings and certifications...

And more trainings and certification

Languages

Based on CEFR language proficiency levels

Portuguese Native English C2 Spanish A2 Norwegian A2

Projects

Micro-Frontend platform

🖰 07/2021 - Ongoing · 3 mos 🖨 Sportradar

- Single page frontend built with TypeScript, React, Import-Maps and Webpack;
- Able to load different apps into a single interface and bridge their communication;
- There is a huge side of CLI tooling and webpack configuration;
- Developer experience is critical, this is the platform to build apps fo;

Formula 1 Trading Application

🖰 02/2020 - Ongoing · 1 yrs 8 mos 🖨 Sportradar

- Real-time frontend built with Typescript, React, Redux and Styled-Components;
- Handle a lot of live data. The data can receive 5 to 8 updates per second;
- There is render throttling for different portions of the screen, performance is important;
- Tested using end to end tests, unit tests and static tests;

Cryptocurrency Order Book (Open Source)

- Highly performant react app targeted to run on slow devices;
- Receives 10+ updates per second, uses throttling based on device performance;
- Efficiently uses DOM and CSS to avoid unecessary computations;
- Built critical components using test driven development (TDD), used Jest;

Booking Calendar

🖰 03/2018 - 02/2020 · 1 yrs 11 mos 🖨 **Sportradar**

- Single page frontend built with React, Redux and SCSS;
- Handled a lot of data, performance was important;
- There is a set of complex filtering with filter composing heuristics;
- Fully tested on critical paths with end to end, integration and unit tests;

Airbnb Mobile Authentication Clone (Open Source)

 $\stackrel{ riangle}{=}$ 2018 $\stackrel{ riangle}{=}$ github.com/alexrohleder/a2 $\stackrel{ riangle}{\mathscr{E}}$ auth-with-firestore-ts-vue.web.app

- Showcase authentication app in VueJS, TypeScript and Firebase;
- · Have a extensive documentation with technical detailing;
- Implement url access control and handle redirects;
- Allows use of social login with Facebook and Google;

Healthcare Insurance Application

 $\stackrel{ riangle}{=}$ 03/2016 - 01/2018 \cdot 1 yrs 10 mos $\stackrel{ riangle}{=}$ **Meta** consulting for **Unimed**

- Multi-page app built with Laravel, VueJS and SCSS;
- Developers had direct access to stakeholders, the domain was well known by both;
- Load performance was critical, many techniques were applied to maintain it;
- Search functionalities were highly optimized and allowed rich queries;

Hiring Platform

🗂 01/2017 - 07/2017 · 6 mos 🚊 **Meta** consulting for **Calçados Beira Rio**

A specialized hiring platform built with Laravel, VueJS and SCSS.

Automated Phone Menu System

 $\stackrel{\mbox{\tiny \square}}{=} 07/2017$ - $01/2018 \cdot 6$ mos $\stackrel{\mbox{\tiny \square}}{=}$ Meta consulting for Sascar

Improving the existing automated phone menu system with PHP and Java.

Invoice System Integration to Government Webservices

 $\stackrel{\mbox{\tiny (1)}}{=} 07/2017 - 01/2018 \cdot 6 \; \mbox{mos} \quad \stackrel{\mbox{\tiny (2)}}{=} \; \mbox{Meta} \; \mbox{consulting for Grupo Greencard}$

Integrated their invoice system to Brazilian webservices with PHP and SOAP.

Brazilian Government Website

 $\stackrel{\longleftarrow}{\Box}$ 07/2016 - 01/2018 \cdot 1 yrs 6 mos $\stackrel{\frown}{\Box}$ Meta consulting for Brazilian Government

Responsible for supporting the website and the CRM, used PHP and jQuery. $\label{eq:crossing} % \begin{subarray}{ll} \end{subarray} \ben$